Guide to the John Nolen Papers,1890-1938, 1954-1960.
Nolen, John papers,1890-1938, 1954-1960.
- Series IV. Professional Career
  - Landscape Architect and City Planner
    - Project Material
      - Flat Oversized Plans
        - Fort Myers, Florida, 1926 (Map-case Folder 37)
          Corporate or Government Entity: Wayne Development Company
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, plans, mostly tracings.
        - Gainesville, Florida, undated (Map-case Folder 38)
          Project Description: University Park
          Job Number: 334
          Corporate or Government Entity: Brown Development Company of Michigan
          Drawings List and Other Details: Residential community adjacent to the University of Florida; subdivision plans
        - Holt, Florida, 1925 (Map-case Folder 39)
          Project Description: Floridale Poultry Farm
          Job Number: 330
          Drawings List and Other Details: White, Col. W.L. model poultry farm. 2 drawings.
        - St. Augustine, Florida, 1925 (Map-case Folder 40)
          Job Number: 317
          Corporate or Government Entity: St. Augustine Realty Company.
          Drawings List and Other Details: St. Augustine Beach, Anastasia Island. Preliminary study, 2 development plans.
        - St. Petersburg, Florida, 1922, 1925 (Map-case Folder 41)
          Job Number: 256
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans of civic center, waterfront development, existing conditions, planning proposals
        - St. Petersburg, Florida, 1923, 1926 (Map-case Folder 42)
          Job Number: 344
          Drawings List and Other Details: General city plan, zone plan, waterfront development, revised general plan, grouping of public buildings, athletic field, tracings and linens.
        - St. Petersburg, Florida, 1925 (Map-case Folder 43)
          Project Description: Maximo Estate
          Job Number: 319
          Drawings List and Other Details: Subdivision plans
        - San Jose, Florida, 1925 (Map-case Folder 44)
          Job Number: 326
          Drawings List and Other Details: "New Community" plan, 1 linen plan, 1 printed plan
        - Sarasota, Florida, 1924 (Map-case Folder 45)
          Job Number: 320
          Drawings List and Other Details: Existing conditions, planning proposals, park plan sketches, tracings and linens, map, 1 printed plan
        - Sarasota, Florida, 1925 (Map-case Folder 46)
          Job Number: 337 Corporate or Government Entity: Villa de Soto syndicate
          Drawings List and Other Details: Incorporation subdivisions; linens, blueprints and tracings.
        - Tamiami City, Florida, 1926 (Map-case Folder 47)
          Job Number: 333
          Drawings List and Other Details: Looks like a New Town plan, including building of Cypress Lake; completely separate Negro section between railroad and highway, cut off from town mill, including school, business district; apparently never built-not listed on U.S. census
        - Venice, Florida, 1924-1926 (Map-case Folder 48-50)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sections, studies, blueprints, linens,
        - Venice, Florida, 1926, undated (Map-case Folder 51)
          Project Description: Artist Colony
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketch plan for artist colony and preliminary construction plan of artist colony
        - Venice, Florida, 1924, undated (Map-case Folder 52)
          Project Description: Bay Point
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plat plan of Bay Point and Lyons Bay area; Preliminary plan for the subdivision of Bay Point property of Dr. Fred H. Albee; General plan for subdivision of Bay Point; Typical Street Sections
        - Venice, Florida, 1927 (Map-case Folder 53)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketch showing proposed treatment of civic center, auditorium, city hall, library and fire station
        - Venice, Florida, undated (Map-case Folder 54)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Unidentified plans
        - Venice Florida, 1927, undated (Map-case Folder 55)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Aerial photographs and an issue of "The Venice News"
        - West Palm Beach, Florida, 1921-1923 (Map-case Folder 56)
          Job Number: 259
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, plans zoning; "colored" area (parks, school, residences) completely surrounded by industry
        - Columbus, Georgia, 1924-1925 (Map-case Folder 57-58)
          Job Number: 304
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, blueprints, linens, large files
        - Savannah, Georgia, 1907-1908 (Map-case Folder 59)
          Job Number: 35 and 36
          Drawings List and Other Details: (35) Baldwin, G.J. (nothing on Baldwin); (36) complete plans for Daffin Park; Improvement plans for Savannah and Chatham Company; city plan, parks layout, station and water approach
        - Elkhart, Indiana, 1920-1922 (Map-case Folder 60)
          Job Number: 240
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, plans, site plans, blueprints
        - Dubuque, Iowa, 1931-1932 (Map-case Folder 61)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Master plan and zoning plan
        - Keokuk, Iowa, 1913, undated (Map-case Folder 62)
          Job Number: 119
          Government or Corporate Entity: National Resources Board subsistence homesteads
          Drawings List and Other Details: Site plan for civic center, 3 blueprints (one titled Russell Vannest Black, planner); Broadside: Electric Power from the Mississippi
        - Keokuk, Iowa, 1913 (Map-case Folder 63)
          Job Number: 127
          Government or Corporate Entity: Keokuk Industrial Association
          Drawings List and Other Details: Map, plans, sketches
        - Sioux, City, Iowa, 1920 (Map-case Folder 64)
          Job Number: 223
          Government or Corporate Entity: Davidson Realty Company
          Drawings List and Other Details: City map, subdivision plans
        - Auburn, Maine, 1923 (Map-case Folder 65)
          Project Description: Pettingill Park
          Job Number: 278
          Drawings List and Other Details: Auburn Planning Board, 1 plan
        - Bar Harbor, Maine, 1907 (Map-case Folder 66)
          Project Description: Hinkle Harbor
          Job Number: 33
          Drawings List and Other Details: Construction and planting plan
        - Cape Newagen, Maine, 1924 (Map-case Folder 67)
          Job Number: 311
          Drawings List and Other Details: Brooks, J.L.; Newagen Inn, Southport, Maine
        - Lewiston, Maine, 1914 (Map-case Folder 68)
          Project Description: Bates College
          Job Number: 133
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans
        - Beltsville, Maryland, 1933 (Map-case Folder 69)
          Project Description: U.S. Experimental Station
          Drawings List and Other Details: 3 maps, subsistence homestead sites
        - Kansas City, Missouri, undated (Map-case Folder 70)
          Project Description: Country Club District
          Job Number: 153
          Drawings List and Other Details: Nichols, S.C. sketches and blueprints
        - Andover, Massachusetts, 1922-1923 (Map-case Folder 71)
          Job Number: 263
          Government or Corporate Entity: War Memorial Committee
          Drawings List and Other Details: Existing conditions, preliminary plan redesign, general plan, map of central part
        - Arlington, Massachusetts, 1930 (Map-case Folder 72)
          Project Description: Sullivan Gardens
          Drawings List and Other Details: Planting plan for Mrs. James B. Sullivan; planting list, estimates for Reginald Hull, Codlidge Hill, Cambridge
        - Boston, Massachusetts, 1930-1932 (Map-case Folder 73)
          Project Description: Boston Port Development
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps and blueprints
        - Boston, Massachusetts, undated (Map-case Folder 74)
          Project Description: Harvard Parkway Research
          Drawings List and Other Details: Blueprints, commercial maps, charts, tracings and sketches from Nolen office of Boston, Wayne County, Kansas City, and Minneapolis Parkways
        - Boston, Massachusetts, undated (Map-case Folder 75)
          Project Description: Neptune Gardens
          Government or Corporate Entity: Neptune Garden Corporation
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans, tracings, 4 copies of drawing no. 2
        - Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1929 (Map-case Folder 76)
          Project Description: Hull Estate
          Job Number: 370
          Drawings List and Other Details: Tracings, planting plans
        - Camp Devens, Massachusetts, 1925-1926 (Map-case Folder 77)
          Drawings List and Other Details: 1 blueprint "Construction group plan Boston 1925 and 1926"
        - Cohasset, Massachusetts, 1912-1928 (Map-case Folder 78-79)
          Job Number: 311, 213, 239
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans, site plans, sketches, blueprints, brown prints
        - Everette, Massachusetts, undated (Map-case Folder 80)
          Job Number: 159
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketches and blueprint of the city
        - Fall River, Massachusetts, 1922, 1925 (Map-case Folder 81)
          Job Number: 300
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketch, plan for War Memorial
        - Falmouth, Massachusetts, 1923 (Map-case Folder 82)
          Job Number: 279
          Government or Corporate Entity: Falmouth Village Improvement
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans and linens
        - Framingham, Massachusetts, 1921 (Map-case Folder 83)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Study for memorial building site, 3 tracings, 1 linen
        - Lowell, Massachusetts, 1926, 1928 (Map-case Folder 84)
          Job Number: 331 and 354
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketches, plans, tracings for Board Parks, Commissioner’s memorial parks
        - North Adams, Massachusetts, 1920-1925 (Map-case Folder 85-86)
          Job Number: 227, 277 and 295
          Drawings List and Other Details: Zoning, existing conditions map, development plans, street arrangement
        - Northampton, Massachusetts, 1914-1915 (Map-case Folder 87)
          Project Description: Smith College
          Job Number: 135
          Drawings List and Other Details: Campus plan (for Smith and others)
        - Northampton, Massachusetts, 1908 (Map-case Folder 88)
          Project Description: Smith College Agricultural School
          Job Number: 65
          Drawings List and Other Details: Construction and planning
        - South Framington, Massachusetts, 1913 (Map-case Folder 89)
          Project Description: Clark's Hill
          Job Number: 131
          Government or Corporate Entity: Denison Packing Company
          Drawings List and Other Details: Sketch and 2 plans
        - Stoneham, Massachusetts, 1912 (Map-case Folder 90)
          Job Number: 96
          Drawings List and Other Details: Square site plan, school planting plans
        - Wakefield, Massachusetts, 1920-1922 (Map-case Folder 91)
          Job Number: 226
          Drawings List and Other Details: Wakefield High School grounds and athletic field, streets, school location, grading
        - Walpole, Massachusetts, 1913-1931 (Map-case Folder 92-93)
          Job Number: 124, 267, 832, 350
          Drawings List and Other Details: School grounds, streets, city center chart of Walpole's growth, layout for school center and town forest, general plan; Memorial Park and swimming, plans, floor plans and elevations for pool and bath houses
          Also, Harriet Nevin's memorial fountains plans and elevations, tracings only for later plans
        - Walpole, Massachusetts, 1911, 1928 (Map-case Folder 94)
          Project Description: P.R. Allen Estate
          Drawings List and Other Details: Survey, preliminary plan by Sibley Smith (undated), planting plan
        - Walpole, Massachusetts, 1913-1914, 1920, 1924 (Map-case Folder 95a-95b)
          Project Description: Neponset Garden Village
          Job Number: 125, 299, 297, 231
          Drawings List and Other Details: F.W. Bird and Son, plans, including plans for Walpole station
        - Walpole, Massachusetts, 1925, 1929 (Map-case Folder 96)
          Job Number: 341, 358
          Government or Corporate Entity: Walpole Home Building Company
          Drawings List and Other Details: Killeen Gardens, Woodland Park, Bird Club subdivision, town commons, entrance to the Francis William Park tracings
        - East Walpole, Massachusetts, 1924 and undated (Map-case Folder 97, 99)
          Job Number: 343 Arch. F and 283 4w
          Drawings List and Other Details: Bird, C.C. Francis William Park: elevations, sketches and studies of gates, bridges, fountain, etc.
          Also, plans, tracings, linen plans, layout Walpole Memorial
        - East Walpole, Massachusetts (Map-case Folder 98a-98b)
          Project Description: Margaret Bird Estate and Charles Bird Estate
        - South Walpole, Massachusetts, c. 1922 (Map-case Folder 100)
          Project Description: Feller's Tavern, Philip Allen
          Job Number: 350 (?)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plan for garden tea house
        - Watertown, Massachusetts, 1921 (Map-case Folder 101)
          Job Number: 242
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, town square, Saltonstall Park
        - Wayland, Village, Massachusetts (Map-case Folder 102)
        - Wellesley Hills, Massachusetts, 1921 (Map-case Folder 103)
          Project Description: Babson Institute
          Job Number: 251
          Drawings List and Other Details: Campus plan, preliminary, revised, tentative plans for building groupings, architect's sketches, sections development plans.
        - Wellesley Hills, Massachusetts, 1923 (Map-case Folder 104-105)
          Project Description: Babson Park and Neighborhood Trust
          Job Number: 271
          Drawings List and Other Details: Topographical survey, elevations, sketch of planned golf course, lot detail, 1 map and 2 sheets of garden fittings
        - Westwood Hills (near Worcester, Massachusetts), c. 1928-1930 (Map-case Folder 247-248)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Francis L. Coe Residence; G.M. Pomroy; Dr. Gordon Berry Residence; J.F. Tinsley Residence; Miscellaneous plans
        - Williamstown, Massachusetts, 1907 (Map-case Folder 106)
          Project Description: William College
          Job Number: 43
          Drawings List and Other Details: Planting plan for Thompson Chapel
        - Flint, Michigan I and II, 1917-1921 (Map-case Folder 107-108)
          Job Number: 182
          Drawings List and Other Details: City, school plan and many parks, large linen plans, maps, tracings, and sketches
        - Flint Michigan, 1920 (Map-case Folder 109)
          Project Description: Parks
          Job Number: 236
          Drawings List and Other Details: Blueprints
        - Jersey Homesteads, New Jersey, undated (Map-case Folder 110)
          Drawings List and Other Details: 3 blueprints, one titled Russell Vannest Black, planner
        - Allwoord, New Jersey (Passaic), 1916-1917 (Map-case Folder 111)
          Job Number: 172
          Government or Corporate Entity: Parce Development Corporation
          Drawings List and Other Details: Brighton Mills Housing Development; plans and studies #1, 3-4, 6, 11-19, 22; blueprint and linen, subdivision studies
        - Bound Brook, New Jersey, 1915 (Map-case Folder 112)
          Project Description: Lamonte
          Job Number: 144
          Drawings List and Other Details: 3 tracings, 1 plan and negative of subdivision
        - Hoboken, New Jersey, 1929 (Map-case Folder 113)
          Project Description: Stevens Institute of Technology
          Job Number: 372
          Drawings List and Other Details: Campus plan of faculty housing, group planting plan
        - Montclair, New Jersey, 1929 (Map-case Folder 114)
          Job Number: 82
          Drawings List and Other Details: General plan of Cedar Avenue School
        - Pennsgrove, New Jersey, 1915-1919 (Map-case Folder 115)
          Project Description: Dupont Company
          Job Number: 217
          Drawings List and Other Details: Dupont Company Village, blueprints showing existing streets and railroads, tracings on linen and paper, colored map
        - Preakness, New Jersey, 1922 (Map-case Folder 116)
          Job Number: 253
          Drawings List and Other Details: Saunders, B.H., 2 tracings for subdivisions near Paterson, New Jersey
        - Riverton, New Jersey, 1929 (Map-case Folder 117)
          Job Number: 374
          Drawings List and Other Details: Map, street layouts
        - Binghamton, New York, 1920, 1929 (Map-case Folder 118)
          Project Description: Vestal Hills
          Job Number: 233
          Drawings List and Other Details: Tracings, plans and sketches
        - Geneva, New York, 1915-1916 (Map-case Folder 119)
          Project Description: Geneva Colleges
          Job Number: 154
          Drawings List and Other Details: Hobart and William Smith colleges
        - Glens Falls, New York, 1926 (Map-case Folder 120)
          Project Description: Broad Access Corporation
          Job Number: 328
          Drawings List and Other Details: General plan of subdivision, 3 additional plans
        - New York City, New York, 1916 (Map-case Folder 121)
          Project Description: Board of Estimates and Apportionment
          Drawings List and Other Details: District maps, 12 sheets accompanying zoning resolution of July 25, 1916 (3, 12-14), 3 sets
        - New York City, 1916 (Map-case Folder 122)
          Project Description: Commission on Building Districts
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps accompanying tentative report of March 10, 1916 for Boroughs of Richmond and Queens: use and area, 7 pieces
          Earliest maps outlining 1st comprehensive zoning in the United States
        - Olean, New York, 1920 (Map-case Folder 123)
          Job Number: 286
          Government or Corporate Entity: Olean Housing Corporation
          Drawings List and Other Details:, Seneca Heights; Rockwell Mayer Plot Housing Project; plans, tracings, blueprints, linens
        - Olean, New York, 1923-1924 (Map-case Folder 124)
          Project Description: Seneca Heights
          Job Number: 227
          Drawings List and Other Details: M.F. Mayer portion of Seneca Heights study and restudy
        - Schenectady, New York, 1922 (Map-case Folder 125)
          Project Description: General Electric Company
          Job Number: 261 and 177
          Drawings List and Other Details: Athletic field and club house tracings, plan of proposed development of the plant
        - New York Regional Plan, c. 1928 (Map-case Folder 126)
          Job Number: 266
          Drawings List and Other Details: Printed Graphic Regional Plan, 24 streets, map of Sector 3
        - Niagara Falls, New York, 1917-1919 (Map-case Folder 127)
          Job Number: 185
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, planning studies, site plans, sections, sites for housing projects, sketches, "efficiency zones" for schools, etc.
        - Niagara Falls, New York, undated (Map-case Folder 128-129)
          Project Description: Housing I
          Job Number: 204
          Government or Corporate Entity: U.S. Housing Corporation; U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Industrial Housing and Transportation, U.S. Housing Corporation project number 404
          Drawings List and Other Details: House floor plans and elevations, engineering and street plans (all blueprints)
        - Niagara Falls, New York, undated (Map-case Folder 130)
          Project Description: Housing II
          Government or Corporate Entity: U.S. Housing Corporation project number 404 continued
          Drawings List and Other Details: Blueprints, some tracings, linen plans, brown print negatives
        - Asheville, North Carolina, 1921-1922 (Map-case Folder 131)
          Job Number: 254
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps and plans, existing conditions, land use, land assessments, public buildings, Pisgah Forest, zone study, street car lines; Tracings, sketches and studies
        - Asheville, North Carolina, undated (Map-case Folder 132)
          Project Description: Beaver Lake subdivision
          Job Number: 258
          Drawings List and Other Details: Preliminary plan, general plan, blueprint,sketches, tracings. Buncombe County
        - Asheville, North Carolina, 1922 (Map-case Folder 133)
          Project Description: Kimberly Tract
          Job Number: 262
          Drawings List and Other Details: Grove Investment's, 2 plans
        - Asheville, North Carolina, 1926 (Map-case Folder 134)
          Project Description: Weaverville
          Drawings List and Other Details: Lake Weaver Plateau Tract, 2 maps (74 misc.)
        - Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1918 (Map-case Folder 135)
          Project Description: University of North Carolina
          Drawings List and Other Details: Campus Plan
        - Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1907-1918 (Map-case Folder 136-137)
          Job Number: 184
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans, maps, and blueprints
        - Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1914-1916 (Map-case Folder 138-141)
          Project Description: Myer's Park and Private Home Landscaping
          Job Number: 114 and 99
          Drawings List and Other Details: Grounds plans, gardens and planning guides for various private homes
        - Davidson, North Carolina, 1915 (Map-case Folder 142)
          Project Description: Davidson College
          Drawings List and Other Details: 2 colored tracings, 1 linen
        - Greensboro, North Carolina, 1915-1918 (Map-case Folder 143)
          Project Description: Irving Park
          Job Number: 143
          Drawings List and Other Details: Plans, blueprints, tracings
        - Kanuga Lake, North Carolina, undated (Map-case Folder 144)
          Job Number: 66
          Government or Corporate Entity: Henderson Finance Company
          Drawings List and Other Details: Summer colony, maps, plans, large linens, and blueprints.
        - Wilmington, North Carolina, 1922, 1934 (Map-case Folder 145-146)
          Project Description: Farm City
          Job Number: 232 and 387
          Government or Corporate Entity: Penderlea Farm City Corporation. Pender County; Department of Interior Subsistence Homestead Project
          Drawings List and Other Details: Government project maps, floor plans and sketches, site plans, reg. map.
        - Akron, Ohio, 1917-1918 (Map-case Folder 147)
          Job Number: 178
          Drawings List and Other Details: Maps, plans, parks, building distribution, industrial property, civic center, population curve, general plan, zone plan and sketches
        - Mariemont, Ohio I, II, III, 1922-1927 (Map-case Folder 148-150, 170)
          Job Number: 241
          Drawings List and Other Details: Set of 12 construction plans, site plans, sketches, sections; Subdivisions, planting plans, tracings, linens and blueprints;"Preliminary Plan of Mariemont: A New Town Situated in the Middle West. An Interpretation of Modern City Planning Principles Applied to A Small Community to Produce Local Happiness"
        - Mariemont, Ohio, c. 1918-1924 (Map-case Folder 251)
          Drawings List and Other Details: General plans, roadway plans and roadway pavements, and railways
        - Mariemont, Ohio, 1922-1923 (Map-case Folder 252)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Street plans, street profiles and street grading
        - Mariemont, Ohio, 1923 (Map-case Folder 253)
          Drawings List and Other Details: Water systems and steam mains
        - Youngstown, Ohio, undated (Map-case Folder 151)
          Project Description: Buckeye Land Company